THOMAS ROSE

laytr2@gmail.com - 07792122632 - 30 Bannerdale Road, Sheffield, S7 2DL

PROFILF

Ambitious and driven Architect, Engineer and Entrepreneur with 3.5 years of professional working experience and two business ventures. I have a keen interest in sustainability, carbon and innovation. I am a highly motivated designer and problem solver with the ability to understand macro to micro scales. I pride myself on the productivity, organisation and time management necessary to achieve great results.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Oct 2019 - Present

Sheppard Robson Architects Architectural Assistant Working as part of an architectural design team in commercial and education science projects. This involved design work, client/stakeholder engagement, logistics and strategic planning, along with managing the output of drawing information for multiple large projects. I have been commended for my technical knowledge, work output and organisational skills.

August 2020 - Present Rose Brothers Digital LLP Commercial Director

www.rosebrothersdigital.co.uk

A small marketing business set up with my brother to develop my client-facing skills and to learn front-end HTML coding. The business has a growing client base, providing an excellent service that has received great reviews. As commercial director, I make strategic business decisions, manage financials and work closely with clients to deliver the product they desire. All completed alongside my university and part-time work.

January 2021 - Present Homeworking Carbon Model Consultant Developing the homeworking carbon model I created for my MArch Dissertation into a consultant service for businesses interested in the carbon emissions of their post-pandemic homeworking strategies.

September 2017 - Oct 2019 Arup - Buildings Engineering London Mechanical Engineer Working as part of a larger design team on large building projects such as a 1000 seater auditorium, office tower, school and museums.

- Solving engineering problems with the bespoke solutions
- Ensuring the delivery of technical information packages to the client and design team.
- Using my architectural knowledge to the benefit of the rest of the team.

January 2016 - Sept 2020 Archive Design Studio LLP Founding Partner

www.archivedesignstudio.rosebrothersdigital.co.uk

A small business founded by a group of four architecture students including myself from the University of Nottingham. By producing high-quality floor plans and feasibility studies for a wide range of landlords and homeowners in Nottingham and London, the business provided an invaluable experience of the architecture profession and building client relationships. It was as much a learning experience as it was a part-time job to help with course costs.

EDUCATION

September 2019 - July 2021 Cardiff University - WSA Master of Architecture

MArch (Hons) First Class (Predicted)

The RIBA Part-2 course continuing my architectural/construction education.

- Dissertation The impact of homeworking on carbon emissions [85%] top of the year.
- Worked throughout the full-time course (5 days a week in the first year, 2 days a week in the second year) - using time management and organisational skills to stay on top of tasks and deadlines.

September 2013 - July 2017 University of Nottingham Architecture & Environmental Design

MEng (Hons) First Class

The RIBA Part-1 course, which incorporated architecture, mechanical, electrical and public health building services, along with an appreciation for environmental design.

- Top of 100 students in final year design work (76%).
- Dissertation (75%) top of the year.
- Maintained a first-class average over a large range of design and engineering modules.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR EXPERIENCES & ACTIVITIES

- Fundraiser and architect Raised £30,000 to design and build a nursery school in South Africa during the second year of my undergraduate course.
- Social Mobility Foundation Mentoring programme Giving advice on career choices to a student from the SMF scheme.
- Tutoring university students on building services engineering and sustainable design.
- Organising and captaining the Architecture football team during of my undergraduate course.
- Read 30 45 books a year for the last 5 years.

PROFESSIONAL REGISTRATION

Royal Institute of British Architecture (RIBA) Student membership: 2019 - present

Associate Member (AMIMechE) of the Institute of Mechanical Engineers (IMechE): 2018 - present

Architecture Part 1 MEng Degree - Accredited by RIBA & CIBSE: Achieved - July 2017

Architecture Part 2 MArch Degree - Accredited by RIBA: Achieving in July 2021

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Hobbies & Interests

Football, Running, Biking, Snowboarding. Traveling, Volunteering and Culture. Meditation.

Learning

Reading; Business, Design, Technology non fiction books and fiction for relaxation.

Software skills

Revit, Rhino, Sketchup, AutoCAD, Photoshop, InDesign, Vray, Endscape, IESVE and Office.

REFERENCES | Available on request